(
"ai_sub_version": "2.9.1",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch"
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 5,
"max": 5,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
高鳴る心臓に祈りを乗せて
With my prayers loaded into my beating heart,
曖昧な夢を描く
I draw a vague dream.
幻想は想像のまま
The fantasy remains as just imagination,
終われないんだ
it cannot end like this.
みんなー！今日見に来てくれてありがとう！
Everyone! Thank you so much for coming to watch today!
答えを永遠と探し続けて
Continuously searching for the answer for eternity,
何者かになりたくて
longing to become someone.
燦々と降る夕立をただ眺めた
I merely stared at the brilliantly falling evening shower.
優しく寄り添って 心が晴れるのなら
If gently nestling close clears up my heart,
翼が生えたような気がして
I feel as if wings have sprouted,
いつだって隣にいるから
because I will always be right by your side.
だって言葉紡いで歌うことが
Because spinning words and singing...
...あたしの運命だ
...is my destiny.
世界にありふれた虚しささえも
Even the emptiness that floods the world,
上書きして
I will overwrite it.
路地裏に咲いた花のように
Like a flower blooming in a back alley,
願いを照らす
I will illuminate wishes...
小さな光に憧れて
...longing for that small light.
名前も持たない歌なんて
A song that doesn't even have a name...
神様なら認めてくれない
...God would surely never recognize it.
ひとつひとつ枯れない花のように
But like a flower that never withers,
昨日の自分にさよならして
I say goodbye to the me of yesterday.
こぼれた涙
With my spilled tears,
うまく笑えなくてもいいかな
is it okay even if I can't smile well?
だって理想は遠ざかってくばかり
Because my ideals keep drifting further away,
もう散々だ
it's already a complete disaster.
どれだけ手を伸ばして叫んだって
No matter how much I reach out and scream,
届かないの
it doesn't reach.
望めばいつか叶うはずって
Because I believe that if I wish for it,
信じてるから
it will come true someday.
どうか歌よ響いて
Please, let my song resonate!
あぁ、心臓の鼓動が今日も
Ah, the beating of my heart...
うるさい
...is so loud again today.
行き止まりばっか足が竦んで 立てないよ
My feet freeze at every dead end, I can't even stand
音のない世界から君を見つけて 連れ出すんだ
I'll find you in this soundless world and take you away
言葉紡いで唄うことが わたしの運命だ
Weaving words and singing is my destiny
世界にありふれた虚しささえも 上書きして
Overwriting even the emptiness so common in this world
路地裏に咲いた花のように 願いを照らす
Like a flower blooming in a back alley, illuminating wishes
小さな光に憧れて
Yearning for that tiny light
君の歌姫になれたら いいな
I hope I can become your diva
Dancing Reed / 作詞・作曲・編曲：アオワイファイ
[Song: Dancing Reed / Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Aowai-fai]
okey dokey返事はいいけど 冗談なら笑えないよ
Okey-dokey, your reply is fine, but if it's a joke, it's not funny
渋態曖昧どっちを向いちゃうの 蜃気楼に手を伸ばした
Congested and vague, which way are you turning? I reached my hand out to the mirage
微熱のような夢物語
A daydream like a slight fever
そんな光は見ない振りしていた
I pretended not to see that kind of light
ざわめく鼓動まだ行かないで
My fluttering heartbeat, please don't fade away yet
幻じゃ嫌だよ 私を奪って
I don't want it to be an illusion, sweep me away
魅惑のdancing dancing night
A captivating dancing, dancing night
拡がって収まんないuniverse
An expanding, uncontrollable universe
君の表情は私の森羅万象を
Your expression completely rewrites
書き換えちゃうかも責任重大ね
my whole universe, you hold a heavy responsibility
一切合切
Everything, absolutely everything
dance dance dance we are dancing reed
夢中になって絡み合ったゼログラビティ
Falling head over heels in this entangled zero gravity
構わず dance dance dance
Without a care, dance, dance, dance
just a dance just a dance
声は闇に預けたまま
With our voices left to the darkness
目を覚ましても離れないで
Even when I wake up, please don't leave me
maybe needy正気じゃないのよ
Maybe needy, I'm not in my right mind
体温が忘れられない
I can't forget your warmth
誰彼そんなじゃないから
I'm not like this with just anyone
独り占めしてeuphoria
Keeping this euphoria all to myself
気にしてない様な言葉は装飾で
My words pretending not to care are just decorations
メイクの様には流せない
They can't be washed away like makeup
360°偽りだって
Even if it's 360 degrees of lies
隠しきれぬような
And I can't completely hide them
私に構って嬉しいなんて crazy crazy love
Being happy that you notice me is a crazy, crazy love
摩天楼から連れさらって
Sweep me away from this skyscraper
君の表情は私の深層心理を
Your expression completely alters
すり替えちゃうのよ責任重大ね
my deepest feelings, you hold a heavy responsibility
過ぎ去ったネオン 残像shooting star
Passing neons, the afterimage of a shooting star
グライダーみたいに漂えば
If I drifted like a glider
幸も不幸もなかった
there would be neither happiness nor unhappiness
指先でまた君を探している
With my fingertips, I'm searching for you again
その声を聴かせてよ
Let me hear your voice
私に構って 教えてよ恋の先を！
Notice me, and tell me what lies beyond love!
拡がって収まんないuniverse
An expanding, uncontrollable universe
君の存在は私の将来までも
Your existence has stepped
踏み込んだのよ付き合ってよね
into my future, so stay with me, okay?
一切合切
Everything, absolutely everything
dance dance dance we are dancing reed
夢中になって絡み合ったゼログラビティ
Falling head over heels in this entangled zero gravity
構わず dance dance dance
Without a care, dance, dance, dance
just a dance just a dance
声は闇に預けたまま
With our voices left to the darkness
目を覚ましても離れないで
Even when I wake up, please don't leave me
みんなー！今日は誕生日ライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Everyone! Thank you so much for coming to my birthday live stream today!
きゃー！コメントも見えてるよー！
Kyaa! I can see your comments too!
最初に聴いてもらったのが「Diva」「Dancing Reed」でした！
The first two songs you heard were 'Diva' and 'Dancing Reed'!
えー、この二つの曲は、あのフェスと、あと去年のね、ドラマの主題歌に使わせて...
Um, these two songs were used for that festival, and also as the theme songs for last year's drama...
使っていただいた曲で、すごく思い出に残っているので...
...and they hold really special memories for me,
最初に二曲歌ってみようかなと思って選びました！
so I chose them to perform as the first two songs!
そして、今回はですね、ときのそらお披露目誕生日...
And this time, it's 'Tokino Sora 3D Showcase & Birthday...'
2026！「ときのそらお」じゃないよ、ときのそらだよ！って
2026! It's not 'Tokino Sorao,' it's Tokino Sora! Haha,
ええ、みんなの呟きを待ってるので、たくさん呟いてほしいな。
Yeah, I'm waiting for everyone's tweets, so please tweet a lot.
トレンドに入るかな？
Will we get into the trending topics?
ねー？
Right?
そして、今回のテーマは、8周年を象徴する、無限をモチーフに
And, this time's theme is based on infinity, which symbolizes our 8th anniversary.
宇宙や星をステージに散りばめて、中毒性のあるビート、
We've scattered space and stars across the stage with an addictive beat...
リズムの曲で絡めた、えー、デジタルパルスライブです！
combined with rhythmic songs... yes, it's a Digital Pulse Live!
デジタルパルスライブです！
It's a Digital Pulse Live!
こちらね、大きな天球が曲によってどう変わるのかを見ていてください。
Please look at how this large celestial sphere changes depending on the song.
そしてね、今年ののんのんは、えー、いつつなので、
And also, this year's Non-Non... there are five of them,
くるくる回転してます。くるくるくるくるくるくる...
so they are spinning round and round. Round and round and round...
そして、夜空にはソラザウルスもいるよ。
And, there's also a Sorasaurus in the night sky.
ソラザウルスはね、なんとね、炎を出せるようになりました。
The Sorasaurus can now breathe fire!
ぽぅっ！
Whoosh!
ちゃんと、アンキモ座もあるんですけど、見えるかな？
There's also the Ankimo Constellation, can you see it?
もちろん、あと今年も新衣装のお披露目や、告知したゲストと、
Of course, there's also the reveal of new outfits, and our announced guests...
あとは、どんな曲を披露するのかを楽しみにしててくだいさいね！
and look forward to what kind of songs we'll perform!
そして、次に行く前に、ぷちお披露目、最初にしちゃいましょう！
And before we move on, let's start with a mini-reveal first!
カメラさん、上を向いてください。
Camera-san, please look up.
はい！
Yes!
はい、というわけで、新しいクラゲヘア、新髪型お披露目です！
Yes! So, here is the reveal of my new jellyfish hairstyle!
それでは早速、ゲストパートに行ってみよう！可愛い、ありがとう！おお、可愛い、ありがとう！
Now then, let's head straight into the guest segment! 'Cute,' thank you! Oh, 'cute,' thank you!
シロ組さんもいっぱいコメントしててね！
Siro-gumi members, please leave lots of comments too!
最初のゲストは、この人です！
The first guest is this person!
GUEST: 電脳少女シロ
[Guest: Cyber Girl Siro]
星を降らすたびに...
Every time I make the stars fall...
心寄せるたびに...
Every time we draw our hearts closer...
迷い込んだ夜はギャラクティカ！
The night we wandered in is Galactica!
明星ギャラクティカ
作詞・作曲：ナユタン星人
[Song: Meisei Galactica
Lyrics/Composition: Nayutan Seijin]
今夜はソラノアイをライトが...
Tonight, the light on Sora's eyes (Sora no Ai)...
嫌に眩しいから...
is awfully blinding.
街のネオンを...
So the neon lights of the town...
さあ取りよせ...
now, gather them here.
明星ギャラクティカ、2人で。
Meisei Galactica, the two of us.
シドけないくらい...
So seductive...
ユラユラ 揺らぐ星が 心まどわすから...
The swaying, trembling stars bewitch my heart.
この夜だけ... whale
Only for this night...
君だけ...
only you...
夜空に 星を 星を 駆ける...
race through the stars in the night sky.
見つめて あなたの表情...
Look at me, your expression...
照らして 明星ギャラクティカ...
illuminates the Meisei Galactica.
見上げた...
Looking up...
夜空は...
at the night sky...
一等星が...
the first-magnitude star...
チラリ チラって光る...
flickers and shines.
チカチカ 踊り踊って...
Twinkle, twinkle, dancing along...
孤独を溶かして...
melting away loneliness.
2人の影で...
With our two shadows,
わー！
Wow!
はい！というわけで最初のゲストは、
Yes! And so, our very first guest is...
シロちゃんだよー！
Siro-chan!
こんにちは！ときの、シロです！
Hello! I'm Tokino Siro!
ときのシロになっちゃった！
You became 'Tokino Siro'!
本当に今日は、そらちゃん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Sora-chan, happy birthday! Thank you so much for today!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
すごいね、格好！
Your outfit is amazing!
そらちゃんという歌姫にお会いできると聞いて、出せるものは全部出して行こうと思います。
When I heard I could meet a diva like Sora-chan, I thought I should show everything I've got.
そ、そういうことだったんだ。
Oh, so that's what it was.
待って、これチャンネルBANしちゃう...
Wait, isn't this going to get our channel banned?
そんなことない！ごめんなさい！
No way! I'm sorry!
大丈夫、大丈夫だから。胸が苦しくなってきました、大丈夫。
It's fine, it's fine! My chest is getting a bit tight now, but I'm fine!
そらちゃん、クラゲさんには、注射器があると聞きます。
Sora-chan, I hear jellyfish have syringes.
注射器？
Syringes?
毒針をぜひ、頭でごちゅんと、シロに刺していただけませんか？
Would you please sting Siro on the head with your poison needle, like 'boop'?
ごちゅん！
*Boop!*
うっ、うう...
Ugh, oooh...
倒れる、倒れちゃうから！
You're collapsing! You're going to fall!
すごい効いてきました！
It's really working!
効いてきた？
It's working?!
皆さん、そらちゃんは変わりました。毒針を持った女に変わったんです！
Everyone, Sora-chan has changed! She has changed into a woman with a poison needle!
私強くなったから！
I've gotten stronger, after all!
そらちゃんは毒針が持ちたくて、可愛いクラゲヘアになったんですか？
Did you get this cute jellyfish hair because you wanted a poison needle, Sora-chan?
違うよ違うよ。私、やっぱアイドルと言えば、こういう可愛い髪型の人が多いかなと思って、そういうアイドルっぽい髪型にしたいなと思ってたんだよね。
No, no! I just thought cute hairstyles like this are common for idols, so I wanted to try an idol-like hairstyle.
そらちゃん、聞いてください。シロも、アイドルでしかないし、歌姫でしかないのに、Divaっていう曲もありますけど、今もう、アイドルであろうと、なんか、なってるのに、...
Sora-chan, listen to me. Siro is also an idol and a diva, and I even have a song called 'Diva,' but now, even though I'm trying to be an idol,
努力してくれる姿がもう、大好きで、食べたいくらい。
I love how hard you work so much, I want to eat you up.
食べちゃうの？
You're going to eat me?
シナモロールみたいですね。
You look like Cinnamoroll.
見て、カメラさん見て見て！
Look! Cameraman, look, look!
これシナモロール？
Is this Cinnamoroll?
シナモロール。
Cinnamoroll.
食べられちゃう、食べられちゃう。
I'm being eaten, I'm being eaten!
美味しい。
Delicious.
はあ、はい、ということで、
Whew, yes, and so...
今日はBANされない発言を心がけていきます！
Today, I will try my best to avoid saying anything that gets us banned!
もうすでに結構シロちゃんワールド炸裂してますけど。
Siro-chan's world has already exploded quite a bit, though.
あの、なんか、こんな大好きなそらちゃんの、こんな場に、そらともさんたちと、一緒に呼んでもらえると思わなくて。ありがとうございます。
I never thought I'd be invited to such a place for my beloved Sora-chan, alongside the Soratomos. Thank you so much.
3年ぶりだよ！
It's been three years!
3年ぶりの元カノです。元カノじゃない、
I'm the ex-girlfriend from three years ago. No, not ex-girlfriend!
そらともさん、一緒に、一緒に、独り占めしないので、愛でていきましょう。
Soratomos, let's cherish her together. I won't keep her all to myself.
今日はそらともさんに、シロの来た意味を分からせたいと思います。そらちゃん立ってください。
Today, I want to show the Soratomos the meaning of Siro coming here. Sora-chan, please stand up.
はい。
Sure.
さん、に、いち。
3, 2, 1...
バニーガールズ！
Bunny girls!
このスクショでいいの？ねえ。
Is this screenshot okay? Hey.
千手観音。千手観音。
Thousand-Armed Kannon. Thousand-Armed Kannon.
そらちゃん、新衣装のバニー衣装、プレゼントしに来ました。
Sora-chan, I came to present you with your new bunny outfit!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
どうですか？
How is it?
可愛い！バニーガールも可愛い！
It's cute! The bunny girl is also cute!
ウサギさんって、万年発情してるので、ちょっとハアハアしてもらった...
Since rabbits are in heat all year round, I had you pant a bit...
可愛い〜！
So cute!
私の尻尾あるよ。
I have a tail too.
そうだ、そらちゃんと言えば。
That's right, speaking of Sora-chan...
あ、尻尾は。
Oh, the tail is...
ちょっと、お触りしてもいいですか？
Can I touch it a little?
いいよ。
Sure.
つんつん。
*Poke, poke.*
あっ、あっ、大変！
Oh, oh, this is bad!
何？?
What?
シロ、発情が止まらないので、そろそろお家に帰ります。
Siro's heat won't stop, so it's time for me to go home.
帰っちゃうの？
You're going home?!
はい。月からみんなを見守っています。このあとも楽しんで！
Yes. I'll watch over everyone from the moon. Enjoy the rest of the show!
楽しんで！ありがとう！
Have fun! Thank you!
とっとっとっとっと...
*Pitter-patter...*
本当に...あっ、なんか出てきてる。
Really... Oh, something is coming out.
ちょっと！帰れてないよ！...
Hey! You haven't actually gone home!
シロちゃんワールド炸裂で、楽しかったね。
Siro-chan's world exploded, it was so much fun.
なんだこれはって言わないでね、みんな。ねえ。
Everyone, please don't ask 'What on earth was that?' Okay?
でも、相変わらずのシロちゃんで、私、一緒に歌えて、とっても楽しかったです。
But as always, she was Siro-chan. I had so much fun singing with her.
マイペースだね。ねえ、マイペースだよ。私もマイペースだから、良いコンビってことだ！
She goes at her own pace. She really does. I'm also my own pace, so we make a good pair!
というわけで、続いてのゲストに行きましょう。この人です！...
And with that, let's move on to the next guest. Here they are!
全部 全部 アンタのせいだ
It's all, it's all your fault
反吐が出るくらいにウザったいわ
You're so annoying it makes me want to throw up
何かに縋って 諂って
Clinging to something, playing the flatterer
期待したアタシが馬鹿だった
I was a fool for expecting anything from you
ご機嫌伺いの八方美人
Sycophantic, trying to please everyone
それ故にアンチな一生gimme
And that's why you get a lifetime of haters, gimme
浅いキャパシティ まいど おおきに
Shallow capacity, thanks for your business as always
つまるとこ人生ずっと地味
Long story short, your life is always going to be plain
「憎たらしい！」「痛々しい！」
'How hateful!' 'How painful!'
無視出来ないのがいっそ
The fact that I can't ignore it makes it even more...
腹立たしい 苛立たしい
irritating and frustrating
そろそろ飽きた自画自賛に
I've about had enough of your self-praise
ライクの反対はアパシー
The opposite of like is apathy
≒繋がれた証
Roughly equivalent to a proof of connection
切り離せない関係
An inseparable relationship
逸らしてしまいたいわ
I just want to look away from it
これは所謂ヘイトスピーチ
This is what you call hate speech
匿名性の声明を生命に載せてんだ
Delivering an anonymous statement on life itself
鳴りやまないサイレン
A siren that won't stop ringing
近づく度に痙攣
Spasming every time it gets close
赤信号にずっと従順です。
Always obedient to the red light.
大体アナタのコト アタシ ダイダイダイダイダイキライ
Basically, I hate hate hate hate hate everything about you
omg情けない 最早バイバイバイバイバイしたい
OMG, how pathetic, I just want to say bye-bye-bye-bye-bye already
脳内も予測不能故に 解解解解解は無い
Even my mind is unpredictable, so there is no, no, no, no solution
どうだい？アタシのコト アナタ ダイダイダイダイダイキライになった？
How about you? Have you come to hate hate hate hate hate me?
あァ百害あって一利ナシ nothing not see
Ah, absolutely zero benefits, nothing not see
もしタラレバ並めてもニコチンだし
Even if I list all the 'what-ifs,' it's just nicotine
i miss youって近付いた結末は凡ミス凡ミス
Approaching with an 'I miss you' ended in a silly mistake, silly mistake
センキュー反面教師
Thank you, bad role model
後味一生消えてくんないわ
The aftertaste won't go away for the rest of my life
よしよし いい子ね
There, there, good child
笑顔振り撒きパラパラいい子ね
Flashing smiles, scatter them around, good child
だけどだけどその本性は？
But, but, what is your true nature?
善悪の区別も付かないの？笑 はぁ。
Can't you even tell right from wrong? Haha, *sigh*.
減点方式で取り巻く環境に巻かれて
Swept up by the surrounding environment in a demerit system
生涯、痛い！痛い！痛い！も聞かれないわ！って
My whole life, saying 'It hurts! It hurts! It hurts!' won't even be heard!
当然の報いにクラっ ちゃっ た
Getting dizzy from the natural retribution
人は鏡なんです
People are mirrors
実のところ 依存は両辺です
In fact, dependency is on both sides
シャットダウンしても付き纏う
Even if I shut it down, it clings to me
己の弱さが不甲斐ない
My own weakness is so pathetic
全部 全部 アンタのせいって
Saying 'it's all, it's all your fault'
反吐が出るくらいに止まんないわ
It won't stop, to the point of throwing up
いっその事切り離せた方が楽なのにナ
It would be much easier if I could just cut it off completely
大体アナタのコト アタシ ダイダイダイダイダイキライ
Basically, I hate hate hate hate hate everything about you
omg情けない 最早バイバイバイバイバイしたい
OMG, how pathetic, I just want to say bye-bye-bye-bye-bye already
脳内も予測不能故に 解解解解解は無い
Even my mind is unpredictable, so there is no, no, no, no solution
どうだい？アタシのコト アナタ ダイダイダイダイダイキライになった？
How about you? Have you come to hate hate hate hate hate me?
あァ百害あって一利ナシ nothing not see
Ah, absolutely zero benefits, nothing not see
もしタラレバ並めてもニコチンだし
Even if I list all the 'what-ifs,' it's just nicotine
i miss youって近付いた結末は凡ミス凡ミス
Approaching with an 'I miss you' ended in a silly mistake, silly mistake
センキュー反面教師
Thank you, bad role model
後味一生消えてくんないわ
The aftertaste won't go away for the rest of my life
イェーイ！
Yay!
まさかね、ダンスまで一緒に踊ってもらえるとは思わなかったの。
I never thought you'd actually dance with me!
だから本当に、誘った時に「ダンスもあるんですけど...」って言った時に...
So when I invited you and said, "There's also dancing..."
「え、ダンスちょっと...」ってなるかなって思ったから...
I thought you might say, "Uh, dancing is a bit..."
「是非！」と思いました。
But you said, "I'd love to!"
本当に。普段ね、こう、こう、右手でどうにかしてるんで...
Really. Usually, I'm just doing something with my right hand...
手持ちマイクで右手でどうにか尺稼ぎしてたんですけど、
...with a handheld mic trying to buy time with my right hand,
今日はダンスに挑戦できたのが自分的にもすごく嬉しかったです。
so being able to try dancing today made me really happy.
一緒に...
Together...
めちゃくちゃカッコよかった！
You were super cool!
いやいや。一緒に踊れて超嬉しかったんで。
No, no. I was so happy we could dance together.
私も嬉しかった！
I was happy too!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much!
コラボどうでしたか？
How did you like our collab?
どうだった？
How was it?
カッコよかったでしょ？
It was cool, right?
頑張ったぞ！
We did our best!
頑張ったよ！
We sure did!
はい、という感じで。この後もね、またライブがあるということなので、
Yes, so that's that. There's still more live show to come,
この後も是非、頑張ってください！
so please keep doing your best!
頑張る！応援してます！
I will! I'm rooting for you!
はい、ということで、Neo-Porteの緋月ゆいでした！
And with that, I was Hizuki Yui from Neo-Porte!
ありがとうございました！ / 緋月ゆいちゃんでした！
Thank you very much! / That was Hizuki Yui-chan!
頑張ってね！ / ありがとうね！
Good luck! / Thank you!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
てうー！ / てうー！
Teu~! / Teu~!
ということで、緋月ちゃんが来てくれました！
And with that, Hizuki-chan came to perform!
緋月ちゃんって言った。間違えちゃった！ゆいちゃんが来てくれました。
Wait, I said Hizuki-chan. I made a mistake! Yui-chan came.
嬉しいね！
I'm so happy!
というわけで、あっという間なんだけど、私、口癖「というわけで」なんだな。今、気づいちゃった。
So, it's gone by in a flash... but wait, my catchphrase is "So..." apparently. I just noticed that.
ここからライブ後半戦です！
From here on, it's the second half of the live!
それでは5曲目、聞いてください。
Now, please listen to the fifth song.
モニタリング
Monitoring.
ねえ あたし 知ってるよ 君がひとり 涙 してるの 知ってるよ
Hey, guess what, I know that you're all alone crying, I'm wise to it.
ビクンビクン 震えてさ 声もダダ漏れなんだわ
Twitching and shaking, your moans are totally leaking out.
正直に言っちゃえば バレてるんだし 聞いてんの？
Honestly, if I had to say, your secret is out anyway, are you listening?
普通 普通 平気だよ？ みんなわかってないだけ
It's normal, so normal, it's totally fine, right? They just don't get it.
「もしもーし。ねえ…大丈夫？…んー、心配だから今からそっち行くね」
"Hello? Hey... are you alright? ...Hmm, I'm getting worried about you, I'm coming over now."
ねえ あたし 知ってるよ 君がひとり 涙 してるの 知ってるよ
Hey, guess what, I know that you're all alone crying, I'm wise to it.
グスングスン 凹んでさ 弱音ヒトカラ？ いいんじゃない？
Sob-sob and depressed, solitary karaoke? There's no harm in that.
朝が来るまで一緒 トーク
Let's talk all night 'til the sun comes up,
もっと泣いたって 何度だって受け止めあげる
doesn't matter if you cry some more, I'm gonna embrace you again and again.
もう我慢しないで いっぱい吐いてね
Let your tears run free, spill everything.
mwah!
お願い君が欲しいの
Please, I want you so bad.
慰めさせてベストフレンド 愛の才能で
Let me take care of you, best friend, with my knack for lovin'.
泣いてくれるかい 君のツライ抱き締めたい
Will you please cry? All your hurting, I wanna hold tight.
ねえいいでしょう？
Please, say yes?
分け合って乗り越えたいんだってば
I wanna show you I care, let's share and get through it together.
mwah!
お願い君が欲しいの
Please, I want you so bad.
笑い飛ばしてホップステップジャンプ さあいこうぜ
Let's laugh it off, hop, step, jump, and let's go!
分けてくれるかい 君に重い暗い思い
Will you please share? It's too heavy for you, your dark thoughts.
ねえいいでしょう？
Please, say yes?
寄り添って救いたいんだってば
I wanna stick by you and save your heart.
見たい見たい見たい見たい見たい見たい見たい見たい見たいの君の中
I wanna see, I wanna see, I wanna see, I wanna see inside of you.
見たい見たい見たい見たい見たい見たい見たい見たい見たい
I wanna see, I wanna see, I wanna see, I wanna see...
ねえ あたし 知ってるよ 君がひとり悔しがってんの 知ってるよ
Hey, guess what, I know that you're all alone vexing, I'm wise to it.
グスングスン 終わるまで 君を決して諦めない
'Til your sob-sob sobs subside, I'll never give up on you.
ねえ あたし 知ってるよ 君はできる子 知ってるよ
Hey, guess what, I know you're absolutely capable, I know it.
つらい時は弱いくらいで丁度いい あたし、きみの味方だよ
Weakness when hurt, it's alright, you know. Me, I'm always on your side.
mwah! お願い君が欲しいの
Mwah! Please, I want you so bad.
名前を呼んでよ いつだって会いに参上
Call my name, and anytime I'll come hither.
君はひとりか？ それは違うひとりじゃない
You think you're alone? That's not true, you're not alone.
もういいでしょう
That's enough now.
ソロプレイはお仕舞いなんだってば
Solo-play is finito, don't you know?
君がどんなときも あたし側にいるわ
No matter how you're doing, I'll always be by your side.
いつも見守っているわ そうよ怖くないのよ
I'll always be watching over you, see, don't be scared.
mwah!
お願い君が欲しいの
Please, I want you so bad.
慰めさせてベストフレンド 愛の才能で
Let me take care of you, best friend, with my knack for lovin'.
泣いてくれるかい 君のツライ抱き締めたい
Will you please cry? All your hurting, I wanna hold tight.
ねえいいでしょう？
Please, say yes?
分け合って乗り越えたいんだってば
I wanna show you I care, let's share and get through it together.
mwah!
お願い君が欲しいの
Please, I want you so bad.
笑い飛ばしてホップステップジャンプ さあいこうぜ
Let's laugh it off, hop, step, jump, and let's go!
分けてくれるかい 君に重い暗い思い除きたい
Will you please share? Your heavy, dark thoughts, I wanna take them away.
吸い取って救いたいんだってば
I wanna suck them up and save your heart.
ねえ あたし 知ってるよ 君がひとり 涙 してるの 知ってるよ
Hey, guess what, I know that you're all alone crying, I'm wise to it.
グスングスン 凹んでさ 弱音ヒトカラ？ いいんじゃない？
Sob-sob and depressed, solitary karaoke? There's no harm in that.
ずっと一緒 もっと泣いたって 何度だって受け止めあげる
Together forever, doesn't matter if you cry some more, I'm gonna embrace you again and again.
もう我慢しないで出してってば
Let your tears run free, let it all out.
はい！ということで、新衣装です！
Yes! And with that, this is my new outfit!
みんな、可愛い？
Everyone, do you think it's cute?
気になるとは思うけど、紹介は後で。
I know you're curious, but the showcase will be later.
先にゲストの方と歌うよ！
First, I'm going to sing with our guest!
どうぞ！
Come on in!
僕らよ 始まれ
Let us begin
碧く 碧く 果てまで
Blue, blue, to the very end
迷いの境目は 開けたバースデイ整
The border of hesitation, a cleared birthday
放り出されそうなバースデイ
どこに居たって足りない
命は一つじゃ足りない
A birthday where I feel like I'm being cast out
No matter where I am, it's not enough
One life is not enough
まだ 瞬くのはもったいない
不敵な夢を見る
It's still too early to blink
I have a fearless dream
どこまででも行けると
どうしてか 信じたくなった
That we can go anywhere
Somehow, I wanted to believe it
跳ねる鼓動 誰を呼ぶの ベルのソウル
そして待って どうしたって 瞬間始動
ガバナンス自分主導
A leaping heartbeat, who is it calling? Soul of the bell
And wait, no matter what, instantaneous activation
Governance, self-led
あっという間に終わる 祭りじゃない
遅れさえも笑い合おう
This isn't a festival that ends in the blink of an eye
Let's even laugh off our delays
共に在ろう
Let's be together
至って 不完全体
故に もっと 強く なってきた
Through and through, incomplete
Therefore, we have become stronger
不服の夜を超え
空白に願い唱え
Overcoming nights of discontent
Chanting a wish into the blank space
諦め崩された世界を
君と二人占めに 転がり回れ
A world collapsed in resignation...
rolling around, to monopolize it with you
混ざり合い そして 生まれ変わるような
Mixing together, as if being reborn
きっと 僕らだけが 成せる パレード
Surely, a parade that only we can make
絶対お見せしたい 新世界
才能超えた瞬間
言いたいこと言いたい
そしたらお終い
どうなりたい？
I absolutely want to show you the new world
The moment we transcend talent
I want to say what I want to say
And then it's the end
What do you want to become?
架空も現実も
ごちゃ混ぜに詰め込みたがり
過去の惜別も
引きずって歌うばかり
Both fiction and reality
Wanting to stuff them all in together
Even the parting of the past
I'll just drag them along as I sing
今はそこに君がいる
未知なるバージョン 駆け抜けよう
Now you are right there
Let's run through this unknown version
まだ名もなきヒーロー
Still a nameless hero
行こうか
Shall we go?
僕らよ 始まれ
Let us begin
碧く 碧く 果てまで
Blue, blue, to the very end
至って 不完全体
故に もっと 強く なってきた
Through and through, incomplete
Therefore, we have become stronger
不服の夜を超え 空白に願い唱え
Overcoming nights of discontent, chanting a wish into the blank space
諦め崩された世界を 君と二人占めに 転がり回れ
A world collapsed in resignation, rolling around, to monopolize it with you
混ざり合い そして 生まれ変わるような
Mixing together, as if being reborn
きっと 僕らこそが 成せる パレード
Surely, a parade that we, of all people, can make
不完全体 トキシック パレード
Incomplete Toxic Parade
そら：はい、というわけで！
Sora: Yes, and with that!
そら：ゲストの前にちょっとね、今...
Sora: Before welcoming our guest, just a moment...
そら：東北の方で地震があったみたいですが、大丈夫でしょうか？
Sora: It seems there was an earthquake in Tohoku. Is everyone okay?
そら：東北の方、身の回りの安全を優先でお願いします。
Sora: For those in Tohoku, please prioritize your safety.
そら：気を付けるんだよ！
Sora: Be careful!
リオナ：気を付けてください！
Leona: Please be careful!
そら：そして、次のゲストはリオナちゃんです！
Sora: And now, our next guest is Leona-chan!
リオナ：はーい！Flow Glowのリーダー、響咲リオナです！ぷらぷらー！よろしくお願いしまーす！
Leona: Hi! I'm the leader of Flow Glow, Hibiki Leona! Pura-pura! Nice to meet you!
そら：よろしくお願いします！
Sora: Nice to meet you!
リオナ：そして！そら先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Leona: And! Sora-senpai, happy birthday!
そら：ありがとうございます！嬉しい！
Sora: Thank you so much! I'm so happy!
リオナ：今日はね、あの、最近めちゃくちゃ仲良いっていうのと...
Leona: Today, since we've gotten really close lately...
そら：ねー、仲良いです。
リオナ：めっちゃ仲良いです。
Sora: We really are.
Leona: Yes, super close!
そら：あと、歌とダンスといえば、なんか今はリオナちゃんってイメージがあって...
Sora: And when it comes to singing and dancing, I immediately think of Leona-chan...
リオナ：嬉しい！
Leona: I'm so glad!
そら：一緒に、あの、歌いたいと思って、呼んじゃいました！
Sora: So I wanted to sing together, and invited her!
リオナ：本当に嬉しかったです！呼んでもらった時！
Leona: I was really happy when you invited me!
そら：嬉しい！
Sora: I'm glad!
リオナ：それより、それより！
Leona: More importantly, more importantly!
リオナ：そら先輩！
Leona: Sora-senpai!
そら：なんですか？
Sora: Yes?
リオナ：新衣装じゃないですか！
Leona: Isn't that your new outfit?!
そら：新衣装です！
リオナ：めちゃくちゃ可愛い！
Sora: It is!
Leona: It's so cute!
そら：ありがとうございます！
Sora: Thank you so much!
リオナ：どんな衣装なんですか？
Leona: What kind of outfit is it?
そら：こちらはですね、アルバムの「Palace」っていうジャケットで使った衣装なんですけど、
Sora: This is the outfit used on the jacket of the album "Palace"...
そら：実際にライブでも着たいと思って、仕立てていただきました！
Sora: And since I wanted to wear it in a live concert, I had it tailored!
いただきました。
...thank you very much.
あら、そらともさんも、そらともさんも「ひゅ～！」って感じじゃないですか？
Oh, aren't Soratomo like "Whew!" as well?
「ひゅ～！」って感じになっちゃうかもしれない。
They might end up feeling "Whew!" too.
じゃあ、あの、シロさんを見習って、リオナが来た意味をね、今から私も、やっていこうと思うんですけど。
So, following Shiro-san's example, I think I'll now demonstrate the meaning of why Riona came here.
何ですか？
What is it?
まあみんなもね、写真がいっぱい撮りたいと思うんですよ。
Well, I'm sure everyone wants to take lots of photos.
そうですね。
That's true.
リオナ直伝のセクシーポーズ写真。どうですか？
Riona's directly-taught sexy pose photos. How about that?
やるやる。
I'll do it, I'll do it!
スクショ大会！
Screenshot tournament!
こんな大会？
A tournament like this?
大会です、もうこれは。
It's a tournament, indeed.
大会だった。
It was a tournament.
あの、セクシーなポーズを直伝、直伝してくれるので。
Since I'll be teaching you sexy poses directly...
それをね、そらともさんに写真撮ってもらうという回でも。
We can have Soratomo take photos of us in this segment.
私はあの、もう画面外で...
I will... go off-screen...
え、なんで？
Eh, why?
あとで一緒に撮るね。
Let's take them together later.
あ、オッケーです。
Ah, OK.
じゃあ、まず。
Well, first...
やっぱリオナと言えば、リオナと言えば、もうこれですから。
When you think of Riona, when you think of Riona, it's definitely this.
これできるかな、私。
I wonder if I can do this...
これ、ちょっと... ちょっと足をこう... 私できない、ちょっと...
This... just put your leg like... Ah, I can't do it, wait...
いろいろアウト、いろいろアウト。
Various things are out, various things are out.
こういうのはどうですか？こういうの。
How about this kind? Like this.
あ、これね。
Ah, this one.
もうリオナはね、いきますから、どこか。
Riona is going to leave now to somewhere.
あ、いいですね、いいですね！あ、いいですね！
Ah, nice, nice! Ah, nice!
ちょっと右手を前に出しちゃったりして。
Try putting your right hand forward a bit...
あ、いいですね、いいですね！
Ah, nice, nice!
ちょっと、あ、いい！上手い！
A bit, ah, nice! You're good!
あれ？そら先輩、セクシーの才能がかなりあるんじゃないですか？
Huh? Sora-senpai, don't you have quite a talent for being sexy?
おおー、素晴らしい！
Ooh, wonderful!
え、あとはどうしようかな。
Um, what else should we do?
ちょっと、あ、いや、いいの？それ。
Wait, ah, is that okay?
そういうことじゃないの、セクシーって。
That's not what sexy is about...
まあちょっと、教える必要なかったですよ、これ。
Well, there was really no need to teach you this.
あ、ちょっと、あ、ちょっと。後ろからのアングルめっちゃいいな。
Ah, wait, ah, wait. The angle from behind is really good.
ちょっと！楽しんでないでよ、もう。
Wait! Don't just enjoy it.
あ、ごめん、ごめん。
Ah, sorry, sorry.
あと、なんかね、こういうのとかね。
And also, something like this.
いやーん、みたいな。後ろからの、イェーイ。
Like, "Oh no." From behind, yay.
あ、いいですね、いいですね。可愛い！
Ah, nice, nice. Cute!
可愛い。色とりどりでめっちゃ綺麗ですね。
Cute. It's so colorful and beautiful.
そらの、グラデーションが入ってて可愛いんだよ。
Sora's has a gradient, so it's cute.
めっちゃ可愛い！
So cute!
え、じゃあ一緒に撮ってくれますか？
Well, then will you take a photo together with me?
もちろん、だよ。
Of course.
イェーイ。そらりおポーズ、考えようって言ったのに全然考えられない...
Yay. We said we'd think of a Sorario pose, but we couldn't think of anything at all...
なんかね、クマと、なんかリオナっぽいポーズが...
Well, a bear and some Leona-like pose...
なんかリオナの公式ポーズがこれなんですけど。
Well, Leona's official pose is this one.
忘れないでね わたしの声を
Don't forget my voice
画面越しでいい ちゃんと愛して
Through the screen is fine, love me properly
ヴァーチャルだって 突き放さないで
Even if I'm virtual, don't push me away
あなたの音にまだ溺れていたい
I still want to drown in your sound
覚えていてね わたしの声を
Remember my voice
あなたがくれた この身すべてを
And everything of this body you gave me
見つめ合う あなたと二人
We look at each other, just the two of us
重ねた息と 音とヒビカセ
Make our breath and sound resonate
真夜中に問う 冷え切った熱
Ask at midnight - cold heat
待ち続けてる 午前零時
I'm waiting at midnight
鏡写しに 飽和していく
Saturating in mirroring
知らない音が伝う
Sounds you do not know
感覚 即 体感
Sense, immediate physical sensation
寝静まる夜と 息遣い揃う
Sleeping night and breathing together
体感 即 快感
Physical, immediate pleasure
錆びたロジック 「今一度」を焦がれる
Rusted logic, yearning for "once more"
感覚 即 体感
Sense, immediate physical sensation
寝静まる夜と 息遣い揃う
Sleeping night and breathing together
体感 即 快感
Physical, immediate pleasure
錆びたロジック 「今一度」を焦がれる
Rusted logic, yearning for "once more"
忘れないでね わたしの声を
Don't forget my voice
次元も越えて 飛ばすシグナル
Signals that fly beyond dimensions
ヴァーチャルだなんて 言わないで
Don't say it's virtual
あなたの音にまだ愛されていたい
I still want to be loved by your sound
覚えていてね わたしの声を
Remember my voice
あなたがくれた この身すべてを
All this body you gave me
言の葉と初の音が交わる
The first sound intersects the leaves of words
この息と音とヒビカセ
This breath, sound, and the hibikase
あぁ、あなたの生んだ音に
Ah, in the sound you created
あぁ、ただ恋をしていたの
Ah, I was just in love
哀しみ 怒り 疑心 すべて 打ち鳴らす
Sadness, anger, doubt, ringing all of them
絶えず叫ぶ 声連ねる
Screaming constantly, linking voices
余熱交ぜる 愛、艶めく
Mixing lingering heat, love grows lustrous
絶えず叫ぶ 声連ねる
Screaming constantly, linking voices
余熱交ぜる 愛、艶めく
Mixing lingering heat, love grows lustrous
魅了されていく
Being fascinated
忘れないでね わたしの声を
Don't forget my voice
画面越しでいい ちゃんと愛して
Through the screen is fine, love me properly
ヴァーチャルだって 突き放さないで
Even if I'm virtual, don't push me away
あなたの音にまだ溺れていたい
I still want to drown in your sound
覚えていてね わたしの声を
Remember my voice
あなたがくれた この身すべてを
And everything of this body you gave me
見つめ合う あなたと二人
We look at each other, alone with you
重ねた息と 音とヒビカセ
Make our breath and sound resonate
あなたの初の音 この声聴かせ
Your first sound, let me hear this voice
音とヒビカセ
Make sound and hibikase
はい！というわけで、最後のゲストは、風真いろはちゃんでーす！
Yes! And so, our final guest is Kazama Iroha-chan!
いぇーい！
Yay!
ホロックスの、強い、イケメン、速い、カッコいい、なんかすごい、風真いろはです！
holoX's strong, cool, fast, awesome... somehow amazing, Kazama Iroha!
いぇーい！
Yay!
おかしいな…
That's strange...
おかしいな？
Strange?
そら先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Sora-senpai, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
おかしいな…
That's strange...
何が、何がおかしいんだい？
What's strange?
リハーサル日までは、あんなにメロついてくれてたのに…
Up until the rehearsal day, you were so head over heels for me...
すごいじゃん、今日…今日のために整えてくれたってこと？
That's great! You mean... you readied yourself for today?
今日のために、ちょっとあの、整えさせていただきました
Yes, for today, I readied myself a bit.
ありがとうございまーす！
Thank you very much!
コメント欄のみんなも、あんなにメロついてくれてたのに、今日は全然メロついてない…
Everyone in the comments section was also so head over heels, but today, not at all...
いやいや、そんなことなかったよ！カッコいい、二人ともカッコいいって書いてあったよ！
No, no, that's not true! They wrote "cool", "both of them are cool"!
え？本当ですか？本当に？ちょっと、もう一回見たいから「カッコいい」って書いて。
Eh? Really? Really? Wait, I want to see it again, so write "cool"!
カッコいいって、みんな「カッコいい」って書いて！
Cool, everyone write "cool"!
あ、可愛い、可愛い、可愛い…いや、可愛いは当たり前じゃん！
Ah, cute, cute, cute... wait, cute is a given!
あ、そうだね。そりゃそうだ。
Ah, that's true. Of course.
ござるちゃんはいつでも可愛い。
Gozaru-chan is always cute.
ほら、カッコいい、カッコいいって！
See, "cool", "cool"!
あ！あ！ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！お前たちの「カッコいい」が義務だとしても風真いろはは嬉しいぞ。
Ah! Ah! Thank you! Thank you! Even if your "cool" is a duty, Kazama Iroha is happy.
あはははは！
Hahaha!
ね、あの、一人でも記念配信で歌ってたけど、それすごく似合ってたから、一緒に歌いたいなと思って呼んじゃいました！
You know, you sang it alone in your anniversary stream, and it suited you so well that I wanted to sing it together, so I invited you!
嬉しいー！嬉しくて！
I'm so happy! So happy!
嬉しくて死んでしまう！
I'm so happy I could die!
生きて！生きて！
Live! Live!
生きて！あ、生きてますよ、生きてます。あ、よかったです、よかったです。
Live! Ah, I'm alive, I'm alive. Oh, thank goodness, thank goodness.
いや、でも、叶うもの…やっぱりそら先輩といえば、ボカロめっちゃ似合うな、って思ってたんで、いつかやってくんないかなーって…
No, but, it came true... I always thought that Vocaloid songs really suit Sora-senpai, so I hoped she would do it someday...
オタクとしてって思ってたんですけど、まさか、自分がゲストとして！
I thought that as an otaku, but to think, I would be a guest!
そうだよー！
That's right!
呼んでもらえるなんて！こんなありがたいことがあっていいのか！
To be invited like this! Is it really okay for such a grateful thing to happen?
でも、一緒に二人で歌ったことがなかったから、歌ってみたくて。
But since we've never sung together as a duo, I really wanted to try it.
確かに！
Truly!
星街アティックだとね、結構ね、
On Hoshimachi Attic, we often...
ツーショットで写ってること、多いんですけどね。
...get shown in two-shots together, but...
そうそう。
Yeah, yeah.
フェスとかでも歌ったけど、3人とかだったから、
We sang together at festivals, but there were three of us,
だから、デュエットってやったことがなくて。
so we've never done a duet together.
確かに！
That's true!
ねー。
Right?
ありがたいお話でございました、本当に。
I was so grateful for the opportunity, truly.
こちらこそ本当に、貴重な体験を。
The pleasure is mine, really. What a precious experience.
いや、こちらこそありがとうございます、本当に。
No, thank you so much, really.
それにしても、
By the way,
今日これ、新衣装なんですよね。
this is your new outfit today, isn't it?
そうなんですよ。新衣装なんですよ。
That's right. It's my new outfit.
どう？
How is it?
おおー！
Ohh!
いや、ちょっと、
Oh, well, actually...
さっき、りおなさんが、なんか結構きわどいことをやっていたんですけど、
Earlier, Riona-san was doing some pretty risqué things, but...
やはりね、あの、ちょっとこっちのクイクイタイプオタクとして、1個いいでしょうか？
as a "kui-kui" type of otaku, may I ask one thing?
何でしょう？
What is it?
やはりオタクというものはですね、一肌脱いだ姿が、すごい気になるっていうものでございまして。
As an otaku, we are naturally very curious about what lies underneath.
この隠されている純白が、この姿が見れるのかっていうのが、すごく気になっておりまして。
We are extremely curious if we'll be able to see this hidden pure white look.
ええ、本当に、だって、この下の清楚感あふれるこれ、絶対みんな気になるでしょ？
I mean, surely everyone is curious about this pure-looking layer underneath?
いや、オタクとして、もう気になりますよ、こんなの。
Speaking as an otaku, this makes me so curious.
そうですよね。でも、この配信の中では、ちょっと見せられないかな。
I see. But I don't think I can show it during this stream.
え？ え？ もしかして、それは、それは脱げるということでござるか？
Wait, wait, does that mean it can actually be taken off?
この配信の中では見せることはないんだけど...
I won't be showing it in this stream, but...
メンバーシップに！ メンバーシップに入れば！
Membership! If we join the membership!
メンバーシップだったら見れるかもしれない！
Maybe we can see it in the membership stream!
はい。
Yes.
いや、楽しみにしておりますので。
I'm really looking forward to it.
メン限に入れ？
Join the membership?
入れ？
Join?
メン限に入れ？
Join the membership?
強制的！
It's mandatory!
クイクイ、だって、脱いだ姿が見れるんですよね。
"Kui-kui"... after all, we can see the layer underneath.
はい。
Yes.
このあとも楽しみにしております。
I'll be looking forward to the rest of the stream too.
はーい。
Yes!
というわけで、そら先輩、まだこのあとも全然続くと思うんですけど、
So, Sora-senpai, I'm sure there's still a lot more to come,
頑張ってください！
but please do your best!
頑張るよー！
I will!
あの、プロとしてお待ちしておりますので。
I'll be waiting for you as a pro.
そうね、またあとで。
Right, see you later.
はい、プロとして、
Yes, as a pro...
プロとして、
As a pro...
あ、やばい、プロの世界に、引き込まれてしまう。
Ah, oh no, I'm being drawn into the world of pros.
あー！プロの世界に引き込まれ、でもござるわね！上品だから、あの、美味しいワールド、お腹壊さないで！
Ah! Being drawn into the world of pros! But I'm refined, so don't get sick in that tasty world!
ありがとう、ありがとう。
Thank you, thank you.
未来で待ってる。
I'll be waiting in the future.
未来で待っててくれ。
Please wait for me in the future.
指なんだ！
It's just a finger!
さあ、何の、何の、何よね、あの、またあとでってどういうことなんでしょうね。
So, what does "see you later" actually mean?
はい、プロとして、何のプロなんでしょうか。
Yes, "as a pro," what kind of pro?
気になる方、後ほどライブに来てもらって、嬉しいなと思います。
If you're curious, I hope you'll join the live stream later.
さて、ちょっとお待ちくださいね。いよいよ終盤戦です。
Now, please wait a moment. Finally, we're in the final stretch.
お水おいちい！
Water is delicious!
いよいよ終盤戦なんですけど、最後まで盛り上がっていってください！
We are in the final stretch, but please keep the excitement up until the end!
もしかしたら、あの子が来ちゃうかもね。
Maybe that girl will show up.
聴いてください。「プレイ」。
Please listen to "Play."
ちょけろ ちょけろ さぁ図に乗って
Chokero / Chokero / Come on, get carried away
いい加減にしろって
That's enough, you say
やめらんないねぇ どうしようもねぇ
Can't stop, can't help it
言い訳なら後で 考えてくれてやる
As for the excuses, I'll think about them later
王道とか下らねぇな 毎回
Mainstream is boring, every time
自意識過剰なやつ 徘徊
People who are too self-conscious are wandering around
みんなが右往左往する間に こちとら地に足つけてきたぜ ハイハイ
While everyone is rushing in confusion, I've kept my feet on the ground, yeah yeah
どうした？みんな 浮かない顔して
What's wrong, everyone, with those gloomy faces?
絵空事大歓迎よ
Air-gazing, I welcome it
diggin' dong ding 現実味ねぇよ
diggin' dong ding / It's not realistic, is it?
diggin' dong ding
早く楽になりたい？
Want to be relieved soon?
いつでもいいよ おねんねさせたれ
Whenever you like, I'll put you to sleep
nothing to do with you
ちょけろ ちょけろ さぁ図に乗って
Chokero / Chokero / Come on, get carried away
いい加減にしろって
That's enough, you say
やめらんないねぇ
Can't stop, can I?
はぜろ はぜろ おおおおおお
Hazero, hazero, oooooooo
責任だってとるよ 墓場までは
I'll take responsibility, even to the grave
堂々とだけさせてくれよ こちとらマイペースなトラブルメーカー
Just let me be confident, I'm a my-paced trouble maker
取扱説明書 隅から隅まで読んでおきな
Read the instruction manual from corner to corner
ヒヤッとしたって なぜかニヤッとしちゃうの おかしーな
Even if you feel a chill, for some reason you smirk, how strange
とめろ、とめろ、とめろ、とめろ
Stop it, stop it, stop it, stop it
絵空事も大歓迎よ
Unrealistic things, I welcome it too
diggin' dong ding 現実味ねぇよ
diggin' dong ding / It's not realistic, is it?
diggin' dong ding
早く楽になりたい？
Want to be relieved soon?
いつでもいいよ おねんねさせたれ
Whenever you like, I'll put you to sleep
nothing to do with you
押せよ そのリセットボタン
Push it, that reset button
消せよ お前のその価値観
Erase it, that sense of value of yours
どうせ何度でも 元に戻せるなら
Anyway, if you can return to the original every time
指くわえてみてるだけじゃ つまらないやいや
Just watching with your finger in your mouth is boring, yeah yeah
so i'm ready
あー
Ah...
思いっきり 前ノリ気味 止まる気ない アクセルベタ踏み
With all my might, leaning forward / No intention to stop, pedal to the metal
ねぇ are you kidding?
Hey, are you kidding?
はい、ちょ、まって
Yes, wait, wait
ここでストップ
Stop here
return to the start
ぜってーやべーよ！
That's absolutely crazy!
話がちげーぞ！
This isn't what we talked about!
早く楽になりたい？
Want to be relieved soon?
いつでもいいよ おねんねさしたれ
Whenever you like, I'll put you to sleep
nothing to do with you
なんて言っちゃって、嘘！
Just kidding, not really!
押せよ そのリセットボタン
Press that reset button
消せよ マインドのろ過化
Erase it, the filtration of the mind
本当はもう二度と 戻ってこれないから
Because in truth, we can never return again
調子に乗せてよ 乗せてみるのが 楽でいいのかもしれないな
So let me get into the groove, maybe it's just easier that way
はい！ ありがとうございました！
Yes! Thank you so much!
この曲「プレイ」を歌わせていただきました！
I just sang the song "Play"!
そして、この曲では、なんとサングラスをかけたあんきもがやってきました。
And for this song, Ankimo actually joined me wearing sunglasses!
どうしてサングラス？
Why the sunglasses?
わあ、取れた！
Wow, they can be taken off!
遊ぶんじゃないの、もう。
Stop playing around already.
というわけで、久々にね、あんきもと一緒に何か踊った気がするんだけど、どう？
Anyway, it feels like it's been a while since I danced with Ankimo. How was it?
5人目のゲスト、あんきもです！
Our fifth guest, Ankimo!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ある意味、シークレットだったね。めっちゃ踊るやん！
In a way, he was a secret guest. He was dancing so much!
そしてね...そんな感じで。
And, well... like that.
まだね、最後にね、実はお披露目もあるんだけど...
Actually, there's still one more reveal at the end, but...
ここでね、まず恒例のお知らせがたくさんあるので、ここからはあんきもと一緒に告知していくね。
Before that, we have our usual announcements, so I'll go through them with Ankimo now!
聞いてください！ まずはこちら！
Please listen up! First, this!
ときのそら 誕生日記念2026グッズです！
It's Tokino Sora's Birthday Celebration 2026 merchandise!
順番に紹介していくよ！
I'll introduce them one by one!
まずは、こちら！
First is this!
Dream! そらとも法被。イラストは、あるだん先生です！
Dream! Soratomo Happi coat. The illustration is by Arudan-sensei!
テーマは、ライブをしてる私、ということで、なんとね、あんきももいっぱいいるんだよ。
The theme is "me performing live," and look, there are lots of Ankimos on it too!
ね！ あの、今までもオリジナル法被自体は、あの、ストアとかで出たことはあるんですけど、
Right! We've had original Happi coats sold in shops before, but...
自分でオリジナルでつくるのは初めてだったので、ぜひライブで着てきてほしいなと思ってつくりました。
Designing my own original Happi was a first, so I made it hoping you'd wear it to live shows!
ぜひぜひ、みんな、楽しんでくださいね。
Please enjoy it, everyone.
ライブに来てください！
Please come to the live show!
続いては、こちら！
Next up is this!
「お部屋でのんびり」ワイドラバーマット！
"Relaxing in My Room" Wide Rubber Mat!
イェーイ！ イラストは、しわすたかし先生です！
Yay! The illustration is by Shiwasu Takashi-sensei!
テーマは、部屋でファンレターを読んでいる私で、
The theme is "me reading fan letters in my room."
こちらでホロカのやつにちょうどいいサイズになってるので、
And this is the perfect size for playing Hololive Official Card Game (Holoca),
ホロカを遊ぶ方、ぜひぜひ、一緒にね、あの、持っていって遊んでもらえたら嬉しいなと思います。
so for those who play, I'd be so happy if you used this mat when playing!
続いては、こちら！ そらとおそろいスマホリング！
Next is this! Matching Smartphone Ring with Sora!
ということでね、前回販売したDJそらパーカーとデザインが一緒なので、
The design matches the "DJ Sora Hoodie" that went on sale recently,
それと一緒に合わせて、スマホも私とおそろっちみたいにしませんか？っていう感じです。
so how about pairing them up to make your phone match with me?
そして、続いては、こちら！ そらザウルスなりきりそらちゃんぬいぐるみ！
And next up is this! Sorasaurus Dress-up Sora-chan Plushie!
みんな、みんながあまりにもさ、そらザウルス、そらザウルスって言うからさ。
Everyone kept talking so much about "Sorasaurus."
でも、そらザウルス自体を言うのは、ちょっと恥ずかしかったから、そらちゃんぬいぐるみ、私が着ていることにする、なりきりぬいぐるみにしました。
But calling myself "Sorasaurus" was a bit embarrassing, so I made it a dress-up plushie where I wear it!
しかもね、フードを外すと、もうピンクの衣装を着てる私みたいになるので、
And what's more, if you take off the hood, it looks like me in my pink outfit!
ぜひぜひフードを取り外して可愛くね、持ち歩いてくれてもいいんじゃないかなと思います。
So you can totally take the hood off and carry me around like that too!
そして最後は、こちら！
And finally, this!
ASMRボイス、ボイスタイトル「届いてるよ、きみの応援」
ASMR Voice Pack, titled "Your Support Reaches Me!"
ということで、部屋でファンレターを読んでいるシチュエーションになっておりますので、
It features a situation of me reading fan letters in my room,
ぜひぜひ皆さん、どんな風にファンレター読んでるのかなと想像しながら聴いてもらえたら嬉しいです。
so I hope you enjoy listening while imagining what that looks like!
そして、フルセット購入特典は、こちら！
And here is the Full Set Purchase Bonus!
直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードと、
An autographed postcard with a foil-stamped printed message,
特典ボイス、ボイスタイトルは「誕生日を迎えて」になります。
and the bonus voice pack, titled "Welcoming My Birthday."
というわけでですね、あの、皆さん急がなくて大丈夫です。
So, you don't need to rush to buy this, everyone.
数量限定ではございませんので、皆さん全員分のサインを書かせていただきます。
It's not limited in quantity, so I will sign postcards for every single one of you!
いくらでも書きますので、ぜひぜひ皆さん、
I'll write as many as it takes! So please,
たくさんの人にグッズを買ってもらえたら私はとても、そらっち大喜び！なので、よろしくお願いいたします。
if lots of people get this merch, Sora will be super-duper happy! I'd appreciate your support!
以上、ときのそら 誕生日記念2026グッズでした！ みんなよろしくね！
And that's it for Tokino Sora's Birthday Celebration 2026 merchandise! Thank you, everyone!
続いてのお知らせは、こちら！
Next, we have this announcement!
はい、駆け足で！ 11月ワンマンライブの「ときのそら 生誕記念先行チケット販売開始」
Quickly, let's keep going! The birthday pre-sale tickets for my solo live in November are now on sale!
ということで、ぴあアリーナのですね、えー、先行チケットが本日から始まっております。
The ticket pre-sales for the Pia Arena MM show have started today!
えー、ファンクラブに入ってる人しかできないじゃないかって言ってた人、
For those who were worried it was only for fan club members,
本日から一般の皆さんも、えー、販売が開始されておりますので、ぜひぜひ！もう12時から開始されております。
sales for the general public have also started today! It actually began at 12:00 PM.
えー、応募していただけたら嬉しいです！みんなでぴあアリーナでライブ楽しもう！
So I hope you'll apply! Let's all have fun at Pia Arena MM!
さらに、こちら！ その現地チケットの特典でもらえるホロカのお披露目！ これもお披露目でございました。
Plus, here is a reveal of the Holoca card you get as a bonus with the venue ticket! This is also a reveal.
えー、ライブの来場者特典として限定ホロカが1枚配られます。
One limited edition Holoca card will be given out to all attendees.
えー、全2種類のうち1枚をランダムで、えー、お渡しするのですが、そちらの1枚を公開です。
It will be given randomly out of two types, and we are revealing one of them now.
えー、私が描き下ろすということで、もう1個の方は、えー、まだなので、
It's an illustration I drew myself, and the other one isn't ready yet, so...
ぜひ、こちらの方で、ちょっと、満足していただけないでしょうか？
Please, with this, wouldn't you be satisfied for a bit?
そして！9周年ライブを記念して、こちら！
And then! To commemorate the 9th anniversary live, this!
スペシャルテレビCM放送決定！ということで
A special TV CM broadcast has been decided!
本日、22時半から23時の間で、
Today, between 22:30 and 23:00,
TOKYO MXさんのところで流れます。
it will be broadcast on TOKYO MX.
一度だけなので、ぜひ見てくれると...
It will air only once, so if you watch it...
嬉しいなと思います。よろしくお願いします。
I'd be very happy. Please look forward to it!
そしてそして！最後のお知らせが、こちら！
And then, and then! The last announcement is this!
お待たせしました！こちらです！
Sorry to keep you waiting! Here it is!
新曲「決意のソラへ」です！
My new song, "Ketsui no Sora e"!
私的には、なんかエモい感じの曲とかね、泣き曲かなって思ったんだけど...
Personally, I thought it was an emotional or tear-jerking kind of song...
でも、ディレクターさん的には、もう泣き曲とかエモとかそういうんじゃない、熱い曲！みたいな感じで、オープニングにふさわしい感じの...
But the director was like, "It's not a tearjerker or emotional, it's a passionate song!" Suitable for an opening...
ぐらいの、熱い曲を作ったつもり、みたいなことを言っていたので...
He said he intended to make a passionate song of that level, so...
このあとね、MVがプレミア公開も予定されているので、
After this, the MV is scheduled to premiere,
各種音楽サイトでも配信もされています。ぜひたくさん聴いてもらえたら嬉しいです！
and it's also available on various music streaming sites. I'd be happy if you listen to it a lot!
はい、というわけでね、とっても楽しかったんですけど、いかがだったでしょうか？
All right, that was so much fun, but how was it for everyone?
告知がね、あの、洪水のようにやってきたと思うので、あとでみんな確認してもらえると嬉しいなと思います。
A flood of announcements came your way, so I'd appreciate it if you could check them later!
え、そしてですね、
And also,
メインは21時半から、アフターライブがあるんですけど、
the main after-live starts at 21:30,
スペシャルあんきもがね、なんとね、見れるかもしれないんだって。スペシャルだよ？スペシャル。
and you might get to see a special Ankimo! It's special, special!
もうこのサングラスあんきももスペシャルではあるんだけど、さらにスペシャルなあんきもが見れるかもしれない。
While this sunglasses Ankimo is already special, you might see an even more special Ankimo!
そしてね、
And then,
さっきも言いました、この放送では...
as I said earlier, during this broadcast...
まあ、ちょっとまだ、脱げないかな、って言ってたの、ありますよね。いろんな撮影会しましょう！
well, there's that thing where we said "maybe not taking them off just yet," right? Let's have various photo sessions!
というわけで、ここまで付き合ってくれてありがとう。あんきもバイバイ！
So, thank you for sticking with me this far. Bye-bye, Ankimo!
サングラス似合ってたぞ。
The sunglasses suited you!
みんな吸い込まれていく。
Everyone gets sucked in.
はい、というわけでね、皆さん、いかがだったでしょうか？
Well then, everyone, how did you like it?
そ、こんなにね、いつもの、情報の洪水が起こっていると思うのですが、ぜひぜひ皆さん、あとで見てもらえたら嬉しいです。
A massive flood of information has occurred as usual, but I hope you will check it out later.
えー、最後はですね、こんだけ「決意のソラへ」と言っておいて歌わないのはどうかなと思いますので、
Lastly, after talking so much about "Ketsui no Sora e," it wouldn't be right if I didn't sing it, so...
新曲で締めたいと思います！
I'd like to close with the new song!
それでは聴いてください、「決意のソラへ」。
Please listen to "Ketsui no Sora e".
一度きりの 私の物語には
In my one and only story,
運命を越えて 煌めくんだ
beyond fate, let it shine!
行こう
Let's go!
みんな、本日ありがとうございました！とっても楽しかった！
Thank you so much for today, everyone! I had so much fun!
ねえ 私より私のことを
Hey, more than myself, you
分かってくれる 君の存在が
understand me. Your presence...
臆病で泣き虫な心に
cast a magic called courage
勇気という魔法をかけたの
on my cowardly and tearful heart.
チクタク 時計の針だけが進む
Tick-tock, only the clock's hands move.
立ち止まってちゃダメだ
I must not stand still.
そう これからも 大きな 大きなお決まりになるでしょう
Yes, from now on too, it will become a big, big routine.
一つ 一つ 重ねてきた
One by one, we accumulated them,
大切なアルバムをめくるように
as if turning the pages of a precious album.
一つ 一つ 叶えてきた今日まで
One by one, we made them come true until today.
そのすべてに君がいてくれた
You were there through all of it.
終わりのない夢を
An endless dream,
ずっと ずっと ずっと ずっと
forever, forever, forever, forever,
追いかけていこう
let's keep chasing it.
行こう！
Let's go!
Xのトレンド入りも果たしたそうです！ありがとうございます！
I heard it's trending on X too! Thank you so much!
ねえ ここで笑い合えることが
Hey, being able to laugh together here
何よりも大事な真実
is the most important truth of all.
チクタク いたずらなハートが痛む
Tick-tock, my mischievous heart hurts.
空回り 空回り シグナルを送るから
Spinning my wheels, spinning my wheels, I'll send a signal,
いてね よ
so stay with me, okay?
泣いて 泣いて 泣いた夜も
Even the nights when I cried, cried, and cried
大切な人生のストーリーだから
are part of my precious life story.
夢を 夢で 終わらせたくないんだ
I don't want to let my dream end as just a dream.
まだ見ぬ景色を 見に行こうよ
Let's go see the scenery we've yet to witness!
もっと もっと
More, more!
輝いて
Shine brighter!
高く 高く
Higher, higher!
飛び立とう
Let's fly away!
奇跡さえも超えて
Beyond even miracles!
皆さん たくさんのコメント ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for all of your comments, everyone!
ひとつ ひとつ 重ねてきた
One by one, we have built up...
未来地図のページをめくるように
...as if turning the pages of our map of the future.
泣いて 泣いて 泣いた夜も
Even the nights I cried and cried...
大切な人生のストーリーだから
...are part of my precious life story.
夢を 夢で 終わらせたくないんだ
I don't want to let my dream end as just a dream.
まだ見ぬ景色を 見に行こうよ
Let's go see the scenery we've yet to witness!
終わりのない歌を
With an endless song...
君に 君に 君へと届け
...may it reach you, reach you, reach only you!
ずっと ずっと 誓うの
I will vow to you forever and ever...
決意のソラへ
...heading toward the sky of determination...
行こう！
...let's go!
本当にみんなのおかげで 最高の誕生日になりました！
Thanks to all of you, this has been the best birthday ever!
みんなのこと 大好きだよ！
I love you all so much!
アフターライブも来てね！
Please come to the after-live, too!
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!